Joyce Carol Oates Papers
Joyce Carol Oates Papers
- Writings
  - Stories
    - "Getting To Know All About You", Intermediate draft (Box 66)
    - "The Girl Who Was To Die" (working titles: "The Store"; "No Pity"), Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "A Girl Worth Two Million" Cosmopolitan, Feb. 1969 (Box 66)
    - "Golden Gloves", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 67)
    - "Good To Know You", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Goose-Girl", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "Growing Seasons and Killing Frosts", Carbon typescript (Box 67)
    - "The Guilty Party", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "Gulf War", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Hair", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 67)
    - "Hammerklavier", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Hand-Puppet", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Handclasp", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Hands", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "Heartland" The Sacramento Bee Magazine, July 26, 1987 (Box 67)
    - "Heat", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "The Heir", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "Home", Work sheets; Ladies' Home Journal, Jan. 1989 (incomplete) (Box 67)
    - "Honeybit" Honey & Vanity Fair, June 1975 (Box 67)
    - "Honeymoon", Carbon typescript (Box 67)
    - "Hostage", Work sheets, intermediate draft; Carbon typescript; Page proofs (Box 67)
    - "House Hunting", Work sheets (Box 67)
    - "How Do You Like Your Meat?", Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 67)
    - "Hull and the Motions of Grace", Carbon typescript (Box 68)
    - "The Ice Pick" (working titles: "There Was a Man"; "There Was No Weather), Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Immortal Longings", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 68)
    - "Imperial Presidency", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Improvisation", Carbon typescript (Box 68)
    - "In Parenthesis", Manuscripts (Box 68)
    - "In the Autumn of the Year", Setting copy (Box 68)
    - "In the Insomniac Night", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "In Traction", Work sheets; The Baltimore Sun Magazine, Mar. 24, 1985; Buffalo Magazine, May 5, 1985; The Commercial Appeal Mid-South Magazine, Jan. 27, 1985; The Milwaukee Journal Magazine, Mar. 17, 1985; Providence Journal Magazine, June 9, 1985; Upstate Magazine, Nov. 24, 1985 (Box 68)
    - "Insomnia", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Intensive", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "An Interior Monologue" Esquire (incomplete), Feb. 1969 (Box 68)
    - "Is Laughter Contagious?", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "The Jesuit" (working title: "The Umbrella"), Aug. 24, 1987; Work sheets; Carbon typescript; The Irish Times (Box 68)
    - "Johanna" Chatelaine (incomplete), Feb. 1978 (Box 68)
    - "The Journey", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "June Birthing", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Kindness" (working title: "The Senator's Wife"), Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "The Knife", See "The Double-Edged Knife"
    - "Labor Day", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Ladies and Gentlemen", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "The Lady with Pet Dog", Typescript ms. (partial, with corrections) (Box 68)
    - "The Last Man of Letters", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "Leave Me Alone God Damn You", Work sheets (Box 68)
    - "A Lecture Upon the Shadow", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 68)
    - "Leila Lee", Intermediate draft (Box 68)
    - "Letter, Lover", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 68)
    - "Life After High School", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; The Atlantic Monthly - page proofs (Box 68)
    - "Little Blood-Button" (working title: "Blood-Button"), Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Little Moses / The Society for the Reclamation and Restoration of 'E. Auguste Napoleon Bonaparte'" The New Black Mask, no. 7, c1986 (Box 69)
    - "Little Wife", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "The Lost Child", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Love and Death" The Atlantic, June 1970 (Box 69)
    - "Love, Careless Love", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 69)
    - "Love. Friendship" Chatelaine, Jan. 1975; incomplete (Box 69)
    - "Love, Forever" (working title: "Demon Mom"), Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "A Love Story", Carbon typescript; Cosmopolitan, July 1967 (Box 69)
    - "Lover", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Magic", Carbon typescript (Box 69)
    - "The Maker of Parables" (working title: "The Writer of Parables"), Intermediate draft (Box 69)
    - "The Man Who Wasn't There" (working title: "The Ledge"), Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Mara", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 69)
    - "Mark of Satan", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Martyrdom", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Master Race", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Maximum Security" (working title: "Correctional"), Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 69)
    - "The Mirror", Typescript ms. (Box 69)
    - "Mistaken Identity", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "The Missing Person", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "The Model" (working title: "Traumerei'), Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Morning", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "The Mother", Work sheets (Box 69)
    - "Mule", Apr. 1987; Work sheets; Boston Review (Box 69)
    - "Murder-Two", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 70)
    - "Naked", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "New Year", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 70)
    - "The Night Nurse", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Nightmusic", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 70)
    - "Old Dog", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "An Old-Fashioned Love Story", Carbon typescript (Box 70)
    - "The Omen", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Only Son", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Our Time", Typescript ms.; Chicago Tribune Book World, May 13, 1984 (Box 70)
    - "The Pact", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Party", Intermediate draft (Box 70)
    - "Passion", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "The Passion of Rydcie Mather" (working title: "The Detour"), Work sheets; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - "The Penitent", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Phase Change", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "The Photographer", Work sheets; Carbon typescript (photocopy) (Box 70)
    - "The Photographer's Model" (working title: "The Model"), Work sheets; Confrontation, Spring/Summer 1986 (Box 70)
    - "Physical", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Picnic", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Plagiarized Material by Fernandes" Sparrow 19 (Box 70)
    - "Poetics 105", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 70)
    - "Politics", Work sheets (Box 70)
    - "Poor Lizzie", Carbon typescript (Box 71)
    - "Poor Thing" (later re-titled: "Poor Bibi"), Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Posthumous", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "The Premonition", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Private Life", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 71)
    - "Prose and Poetry", Carbon typescript (fragment) (Box 71)
    - "The Psychoanalytical Love Affair" Cosmopolitan, Sept. 1964 (Box 71)
    - "Puppies", Carbon typescript (Box 71)
    - "Puzzle" Redbook Magazine, Nov. 1970 (Box 71)
    - "Quarrel", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Questions", Intermediate draft; Playboy, Jan. 1987 (Box 71)
    - "The Radio Astronomer" (working title: "Lookback Time"), Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "The Reliquary", Carbon typescript (Box 71)
    - "The Revenge of the Foot, 1970", Work sheets; Salmagundi, Fall 1995 (photocopy) (Box 71)
    - "Romance", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Running" (working titles: "Hunger"; "The Trap"), Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Satan's Children" (chapter from Man Crazy), Typescript ms. (Box 71)
    - "Scars", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 71)
    - "Schroeder's Stepfather", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Secrets" Mademoiselle, Nov. 1986 (Box 71)
    - "Señorita", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "A Sentimental Encounter", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "The Sepulchre", Work sheets; DoubleTake, Spring 1996 (photocopy) (Box 71)
    - "Shadows of the Evening", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Shame" The Atlantic Monthly, June 1968 (Box 71)
    - "Shelter", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Shopping", Work sheets (Box 71)
    - "Shot", June 1990; Work sheets; Seventeen (Box 71)
    - "Silver Storm", Carbon typescript (photocopy) (Box 72)
    - "Sisters", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 72)
    - "The Sky-Blue Ball", Work sheets; Typescript ms. "early version" (Box 72)
    - "The Soldier", Work sheets; Confrontation, Spring/Summer 1986 (Box 72)
    - "Sonata", Carbon typescript (Box 72)
    - "Sonata Quasi Una Fantasia", Carbon typescript (Box 72)
    - "The Stalker", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Stroke", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Sunday Dinner", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 72)
    - "Sundays in Summer", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Superstitious", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Surf City", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Sweet!", Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 72)
    - "The Sweet Enemy", Typescript (photocopy) (Box 72)
    - "The Swimmers", Work sheets; Playboy - uncorrected proof (Box 72)
    - "The Tattoo" Mademoiselle, July 1977 (Box 72)
    - "The Temple", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Testimony", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Thanksgiving" (working title: "The Store"), Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "Thieves", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 72)
    - "Tick", Work sheets (Box 72)
    - "A Touch of the Flu", Intermediate draft (Box 72)
    - "The Track", Work sheets; Gentleman's Quarterly, Sept. 1988 (Box 72)
    - "Transfigured Night", Work sheets; The Boston Globe Magazine, Nov. 27, 1988 (Box 73)
    - "Turquoise", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Twins", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Two Doors", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Ugly", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "The Undesirable Table", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Unprintable", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "An Unsolved Crime", Carbon typescript (Box 73)
    - "An Urban Paradox", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Valentine", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 73)
    - "The Victim", Work sheets; Carbon typescript (Box 73)
    - "The Vision", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "Visitation Rights" (working title: "My Sister's Son"), Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "The Wake", Work sheets (Box 73)
    - "The Way Back In From Out There", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 73)
    - "The Way We Live", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 73)
    - "We Were Worried About You" (working title: "Sunday Drive"), Work sheets (Box 74)
    - "The Wedding Party", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 74)
    - "Wednesday" Esquire, Aug. 1970 (Box 74)
    - "The Welsh Girl" The Boston Globe Magazine, Mar. 23, 1986 (Box 74)
    - "What Herbert Breuer and I Did to Each Other" McCall's, Apr. 1970 (Box 74)
    - "What Is the Connection Between Men and Women" Mademoiselle, Feb. 1970 (Box 74)
    - "Where Are You Going? Where Have You Been?" Ny Selecta, Oct. 1975 (Box 74)
    - "Where Is Here" (working titles: "Strange Attractor"; "Visit"), Work sheets; Chicago Tribune Magazine, April 1, 1990 (partial) (Box 74)
    - "Where the Continent Ends", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 74)
    - "The White Cat", Work sheets (Box 74)
    - "White Trash", Intermediate draft (Box 74)
    - "Why Did You Cry for Me?" Cosmopolitan, July 1964 (Box 74)
    - "Why Don't You Come Live With Me It's Time" (working title: "The Bridge"), Work sheets; Carbon typescript (Box 74)
    - "The Wig", Intermediate draft (Box 74)
    - "Will You Always Love Me?" (working title: "The Hearing"), Work sheets (Box 74)
    - "The Woman Who Disappeared", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 74)
    - "Yarrow", Intermediate draft (Box 74)
    - "You" Cosmopolitan, Feb. 1970 (Box 74)
    - "You Petted Me and I Followed You Home", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 74)
    - "Zombie", Work sheets; Typescript draft; Typescript ms.; The New Yorker (page proofs, with note from Alice Quinn) (Box 74)
    - Unpublished stories, tentative titles
      - "The Adulterer" (alternate title: "I Could Be Wrong"), Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "Assault", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "Boy Looking Into Infinity", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "Fire", Intermediate draft (Box 75)
      - "The Girl Without Hands" (alternate titles: "A Manhattan Romance"; "The New York Romance"), Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "The Gorge", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "Grief", Intermediate draft (Box 75)
      - "A Letter of Love to One Who Has Abandoned Me", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 75)
      - "Lovers", Carbon typescript (Box 75)
      - "No Pity", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "Pregnant", Intermediate draft (Box 75)
      - "Semester", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "There Was Once, Many Years Ago", Typescript, with revisions (Box 75)
      - "The Thief of Breath" (alternate titles: "Catastrophe"; "Poor Puss"), Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "The Thing-Without-a Face", Work sheets (Box 75)
      - "train", Intermediate draft (Box 75)
      - "Why Can't I Share Your Grief?", Work sheets (Box 75)
  - Miscellany
    - Course plans for English seminars at University of Windsor and Princeton (Box 76)
    - Excerpts
      - Cybele - "Matchen" (Chapter 7 "Game") [n.p.], undated (Box 76)
      - Lives of the Twins [n.p.] (fragment), undated (Box 76)
      - them [n.p.], undated (Box 76)
    - Letters to Editors (Box 76)
    - Report - AWP Short Story Competition, 1980 (Box 76)
    - Unpublished novels/novellas
      - "Constantine", Intermediate draft; 6 folders (Box 76)
      - "The Evening and the Morning"
        - Intermediate draft, 3 folders (Box 76)
        - Intermediate draft (carbon), 3 folders (Box 76)
      - "Graywolf: Life and Times"
        - Intermediate draft, 5 folders (Box 77)
        - Intermediate draft (carbon), 5 folders (Box 77)
      - "How Lucien Florey Died, and Was Born", See Writings: Miscellany: "How Lucien Florey Died, and Was Born" (Box 77A)
      - "Jigsaw", Intermediate draft; 3 folders (Box 77)
      - "How Lucien Florey Died, and Was Born", Typescript ms. (partial); Readers' reports (Box 77A)
- Memorabilia
  - Audiocassettes, See Memorabilia: Audiocassettes (Box 93)
  - Audiotape, See Memorabilia: Audiotape (Box 93)
  - Awards
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters certificate of election to membership, 1978 (Box 78)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences certificate of election as Fellow of the Society, 1992 (Box 78)
    - American Association of University Women. New York City Branch Woman of Achievement identification badge and plaque, 1990 (Box 78)
    - Arts Council of Princeton certificate, 1992 (Box 78)
    - [Elmer H.] Bobst Award in Arts and Letters, 1990; Certificate, program; Medal (Box 78)
    - The Boston Book Review Lilla Fisk Rand Fiction Prize certificate, 1995 (Box 78)
    - Honorary Citizen of Louisville certificate, 1995 (Box 78)
    - Honorary degrees
      - Bethany College, 1993 (Box 78)
      - Drexel University, 1994 (Box 78)
      - Georgian Court College, 1988 (Box 78)
      - Gettysburg College, 1988 (Box 78)
      - Rutgers University, 1997 (Box 78)
      - Skidmore College, 1989 (Box 79)
      - Trenton State College, 1990 (Box 79)
      - University of Michigan, 1992; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Ursinius College, 1996 (Box 79)
    - Lutheran Settlement House Women's Program International Women's Day Award of Honor plaque, 1995 (Box 79)
    - [John P.] McGovern Award medal (Box 79)
    - Mystery Writers of America Edgar Allan Poe Award for Do With Me What You Will (Box 80)
    - National Society of Literature and the Arts certificate of membership (Box 80)
    - New Jersey Women of Achievement certificate of recognition, 1989 (Box 80)
    - New York Women in Communications, Inc. Matrix Award in Books plaque, 1982 (Box 80)
    - [Richard and Hinda] Rosenthal Foundation Award for the Novel, 1968 (Box 80)
    - Saint Louis Literary Award, 1988 (Box 80)
  - Boxing-related
    - Tickets, press passes, slides (Box 80)
  - Criticism and interpretation (by author)
    - Bender, Eileen T. (Box 80)
    - Berman, Harry J. (Box 80)
    - Burleson, Donald R. (Box 80)
    - Chi, Yuan-Wen (Box 80)
    - Cologne-Brookes, Gavin (Box 80)
    - Couzens, Gary (Box 80)
    - Creighton, Joanne V. (Box 80)
    - Eagan, James (Box 80)
    - Fossum, Robert H. (Box 80)
    - Gaffney, Karen (Box 80)
    - Hobgood, Jennifer (Box 80)
    - Inage, Ritsuko (Box 80)
    - Johnson, Greg, includes correspondence from Johnson (Box 80)
    - Labrie, Ross (Box 80)
    - Malin, Irving (Box 80)
    - Manning, Gerald F. (Box 80)
    - Nussbaum, Martha (Box 80)
    - Pease, Roland (Box 80)
    - Rammohan, Dheepa (Box 80)
    - Robinson, Sally (Box 80)
    - Robson, Mark (Box 80)
    - Ross, Steven Paul (Box 80)
    - Rudell, Lioba (Box 80)
    - Strandberg, Victor (Box 80)
    - Waller, G. F. (Box 80)
    - Woodall, Chris (Box 80)
    - Xin, Chen (Box 80)
    - Zins, Daniel L. (Box 80)
  - Financial
    - Royalty statements, 1974-1994; 3 folders of 4 (Box 80)
    - Royalty statements, 1995-1997; 1 folder of 4 (Box 81)
  - Legal
    - Assignments of copyright, 4 folders (Box 81)
    - Contracts, 1968-1982; 13 folders of 34 (Box 81)
    - Contracts, 1983-1991; 12 folders of 34 (Box 82)
    - Contracts, 1992-1997; no year; 9 folders of 34 (Box 83)
    - Copyright certificates (Box 83)
  - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 83)
  - Printed Material
    - Clippings, 1965-1993; 27 folders of 33 (Box 84)
    - Clippings, 1994-1998; undated; 6 folders of 33 (Box 85)
    - Publicity
      - Books
        - American Appetites (Box 85)
        - Angel of Light (Box 85)
        - Anonymous Sins and Other Poems (Box 85)
        - The Assassins (Box 85)
        - The Assignation (Box 85)
        - Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart (Box 85)
        - Bellefleur (Box 85)
        - Black Water (Box 85)
        - A Bloodsmoor Romance (Box 85)
        - Childwold (Box 85)
        - Contraries: Essays (Box 85)
        - Crossing the Border (Box 85)
        - Do With Me What You Will (Box 85)
        - The Edge of Impossibility (Box 85)
        - Expensive People (Box 85)
        - The Fabulous Beasts (Box 85)
        - First Love (Box 85)
        - First Person Singular: Writers on Their Craft (Box 85)
        - Foxfire (Box 85)
        - A Garden of Earthly Delights (Box 85)
        - George Bellows: American Artist (Box 85)
        - The Goddess and Other Women (Box 85)
        - Haunted: Tales of the Grotesque (Box 85)
        - Heat and Other Stories (Box 85)
        - I Lock My Door Upon Myself (Box 85)
        - Last Days: Stories (Box 85)
        - Lives of the Twins (Box 85)
        - Love and Its Derangements (Box 85)
        - Marriages and Infidelities (Box 85)
        - Marya: a Life (Box 85)
        - Mysteries of Winterthurn (Box 85)
        - Nemesis (Box 85)
        - Night-Side: Eighteen Tales (Box 85)
        - On Boxing (Box 85)
        - The Oxford Book of American Short Stories (Box 85)
        - The Poisoned Kiss and Other Stories (Box 85)
        - Raven's Wing (Box 85)
        - The Rise of Life on Earth (Box 85)
        - A Sentimental Education (Box 85)
        - Snake Eyes (Box 85)
        - Solstice (Box 85)
        - Son of the Morning (Box 85)
        - The Sophisticated Cat (Box 85)
        - Soul/Mate (Box 86)
        - them (Box 86)
        - The Time Traveler (Box 86)
        - Twelve Plays (Box 86)
        - Unholy Loves (Box 86)
        - Upon the Sweeping Flood (Box 86)
        - We Were the Mulvaneys (Box 86)
        - What I Lived For (Box 86)
        - The Wheel of Love (Box 86)
        - Will You Always Love Me? (Box 86)
        - With Shuddering Fall (Box 86)
        - Wonderland (Box 86)
        - You Must Remember This (Box 86)
        - Zombie (Box 86)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 86)
    - Publicity and programs
      - Conferences, 1973-1997; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Lectures, readings, 1975-1996; undated; 4 folders (Box 86)
      - Plays, film adaptations (by title)
        - "The Adoption", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 86)
        - "American Holiday", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY; Los Angeles Theatre Academy (Box 86)
        - "An American Triptych", Long Wharf Theatre, New Haven, CT) (Box 86)
        - "Bad Girls", Contemporary American Theater Festival, Shepherdstown, WV; Georgia Repertory Theatre (Box 86)
        - "Black", Contemporary American Theater Festival, Shepherdstown, WV; Williamstown Theatre Festival, Williamstown, MA; Women's Project and Productions, New York, NY (Box 86)
        - "Black Water", American Music Theater Festival, Philadelphia, PA (Box 86)
        - "The Changeling", Rider College (Box 86)
        - "Cry Me a River", Cambridge Theatre Company (Box 86)
        - "Darling I'm Telling You", Risley Theatre, Cornell University (Box 86)
        - "Dramatic Shorts by Joyce Carol Oates", Manhattan Theatre Club (Box 86)
        - "The Eclipse", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 86)
        - "Foxfire", film adaptation (Box 86)
        - "Friday Night/The Rehearsal", Voltaire, Chicago (Box 86)
        - "Friday Night/The Secret Mirror", University of Pennsylvania Theatre Arts Program (Box 86)
        - "Greensleeves", Actors Studio, New York, NY; John Drew Theater, Guild Hall, East Hampton, NY (Box 87)
        - "Gulf War", Burning House Group, Minneapolis; Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "Gulf War/Black", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 87)
        - "Heat", Penlight Theatre, Minneapolis (Box 87)
        - "Here She Is!", New Directions Theater, New York, NY; Philadelphia Festival Theatre; Turnip Theatre Company, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "Homesick", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 87)
        - "How Do You Like Your Meat?", Long Wharf Theatre, New Haven, CT (Box 87)
        - "I Stand Before You Naked", American Place Theatre, New York, NY; Attic Theatre Ensemble, Los Angeles; British production: Cakes and Ale Theatre; French production: Robert Cordier; Mount Holyoke College; The Schoolhouse, Croton Falls, NY; West Coast Ensemble, Hollywood; The Wooden-O, Los Angeles (Box 87)
        - "In Darkest America", Actors Theatre of Louisville (Box 87)
        - "The Interview", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 87)
        - "The Interview/Homesick", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "Joyce Carol Oates: Stories", Northwestern University (Box 87)
        - "The Key/Tone Clusters", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 87)
        - "Ontological Proof of My Existence", Cubiculo Theatre, New York, NY; Ernie Martin Theatre, New York, NY; Swedish production: "Hur Jag Undrar Vem Jag Ar"; Thunder Road Ensemble, Chicago (Box 87)
        - "The Passion of Henry David Thoreau", New Dramatists, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "The Perfectionist", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 87)
        - "Presque Isle", Theater of the Open Eye, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "Procedure", Action Theatre, Louisville, KY; Actors Theatre of Louisville: 1991; Actors Theatre of Louisville: 1992 (Box 87)
        - "The Rehearsal", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 87)
        - "The Secret Mirror", Attic Theatre Ensemble, Los Angeles (Box 87)
        - "Smooth Talk", film adaptation (Box 87)
        - "Spoils", German production: "Die Beute" (Box 87)
        - "Sunday Dinner", American Place Theatre, New York, NY; The Body Politic, Chicago (Box 87)
        - "The Sweet Enemy", Actors Studio Workshop Production (Box 87)
        - "Tone Clusters", Manbites Dog Theater Company, Duke University; Theatre du Rond-Point, Paris; Women's Ensemble Theatre Company, Philadelphia (Box 87)
        - "The Triumph of the Spider Monkey", various productions (Box 87)
        - "The Truth-Teller", Circle Repertory Company (Box 87)
        - "Where Is Here?", Berkshire Theatre Festival (Box 87)
        - "Wild Oates", Central Michigan University Theatre (Box 87)
        - "The Woman Who Laughed", Sharon Stage, Sharon, CT (Box 87)
        - Miscellaneous A-Z (Box 87)
    - Reviews (by title)
      - "The Adoption", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 88)
      - All the Good People I've Left Behind (Box 88)
      - American Appetites, 2 folders (Box 88)
      - American Gothic Tales (Box 88)
      - "American Holiday", Camino Theatre, City College of New York (Box 88)
      - Angel Fire: Poems (Box 88)
      - Angel of Light, 2 folders (Box 88)